Yi-Lu Wu (Lulu Wu)

I am a software engineer with an Animal Science background. Fueled by a newfound love for coding, I have shifted my focus from Scientific research to Computer Science. I am looking forward to applying my Computer Science knowledge to practical scenarios while gaining a deeper understanding of its real-world implications.

(949) 880-6939

sky110423@gmail.com

Irvine, CA, 92620









JOB EXPERIENCE



Tutor (IVC-Student Success Center)

Irvine Valley College, Irvine, CA

🗂 Jan. 2023 – Present

 Helped other students learn C, C++, Python, Java, Data Structure, Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, and Microsoft Excel.



Research Assistant,

O National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

Feb. 2022 – Jul. 2022

- Used Python to group the experimental piglets and shared the application with my peers.
- Analyzed and visualized bioinformation data of multiple scientific studies.
- Publication: Wang, S.-Y., Chen, Y.-P., Huang, R.-F., Wu, Y.-L., Ho, S.-T., Li, K.-Y., Watanabe, K., & Chen, M.-J. (2022). Subspecies classification and comparative genomic analysis of *Lactobacillus kefiranofaciens* HL1 and M1 for potential niche-specific genes and pathways. *Microorganisms*, 10(8), 1637. https://doi.org/10.3390/microorganisms10081637



R&D Specialist

• Chow food biotechnology Co., Ltd, Taiwan

Sep. 2018 - Sep. 2021

- Completed team project on clean-label product development.
- Co-organized exhibitions and led multiple teams with people from different backgrounds.

PROJECTS

- Animal Grouper: To resolve an experimental issue during my graduate, I utilized Python and developed a solution that saved more than 90% of hands-on time. I also developed a GUI for the application and shared it with my peers.
- My Website: Using Figma to design and build the app with React, I
 have learned to implement competitor analysis, performance
 optimization, and troubleshooting while making a website.
- **Zoolleyball** (Volleyball Game): Utilizing Pygame, I developed a volleyball mini-game and learned how to design game mechanics and apply data structure to make the game effective.
- Vision Al Categorizer: I applied Google Vision API in Java to analyze and categorize images, subsequently generating classifications. I gained precious experience in identifying problems and debugging them.
- Al Copywriter: Eliminating prompt complexities, I utilized the Streamlit framework to build an interface and applied powerful OpenAl's GPT-3.5 model to generate a copywrite.

EDUCATION

(Undergraduate) AS in Computer Science, Irvine Valley College, CA, USA, Sep. 2016 – Aug. 2018 (GPA: 3.9/4.3)

 Took C, C++, Java, Python, computer discrete mathematics, computer organization, and assembly classes.

Master's Degree Animal Science and Technology, *National Taiwan University*, Sep. 2016 – Aug. 2018 (GPA: 3.9/4.3)

- Isolated and identified lipase-producing microorganisms from food for margarine production.
- Presented research achievements in multiple global conferences and got an honorable mention in the 2017 Taiwan Association for Lactic Acid Bacteria poster competition.
- The 30th Gemfont Co. scholarship (award for outstanding student) in
 2017

Bachelor's Degree Animal Science, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan, Sep. 2012 – July 2016 (GPA: 3.8/4.3)

- Committed as the Vice President of the school volleyball team and led the team to the University Volleyball League.
- Assigned Student Council member assisting with managing student activities.
- Academic Excellence Award (awards for exemplary academic performance) in 2014.

SKILLS

Programming language: C, C++, Python, Java, JavaScript (HTML, Pug, CSS, SCSS/SaSS).

Frameworks and library:
Streamlit, Pygame, React, Node.js.

Development tools: SQLite, MongoDB, Git, Docker.

Others:

Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Blender, Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint.